# John Foderaro

johnfoderaro@icloud.com • https://jfod.me • Tinton Falls, NJ • 732-766-9484

### **Summary**

Software Engineer specializing in the Node.js ecosystem. Strong understanding of asynchronous programming for both the server and the client. Extensive experience in developing web application, internal tools, and APIs that are highly performant, maintainable, testable and scalable.

### **Expertise**

JavaScript, Node.js, React, Angular, Express, Electron, Webpack, Mongo, SQL, API design and development, npm, Git, NGINX, Apache, IIS, Linux, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less, jOuery, oAuth2, TDD.

### **Experience**

WorkWave Holmdel, NJ

# Software Engineer April 2018 - Present

Currently engineering WorkWave's flagship SaaS companion product with a complete front-end rewrite in JavaScript. Spearheading re-development efforts for this project utilizing Node.js — specifically React, Webpack, Babel, and other related modern front-end libraries. This will result in an enhanced user experience for end users and will provide a blueprint for modernizing additional pieces of the larger software suite.

Works within an agile development team of approximately 15 individuals, ranging from engineers and UI/UX designers to product owners and QA, focusing upon developing and deploying new features for WorkWave's PestPac web application which reaches an audience of about 11,000 users.

WorkWave Holmdel, NJ

## **Full Stack Web Developer**

July 2014 - April 2018

Architected and developed a unified JavaScript technology stack for the internal and external marketing departments, using Node.js to offer a modern RESTful API around GitHub's REST API which automated website testing and deployment. Engineered several tools to assist development efforts, specifically, static site generators and automated development workflows that removed much of the friction, overhead, and manual/repetitive tasks that had been previously incurred due to outdated monolithic CMS solutions.

Mentored Junior Web Developer in modern JavaScript (ES6+) and general web development best practices.

NBC Universal New York, NY

### **Technical SEO Specialist**

March 2013 - July 2014

Lead several initiatives for the creation of SEO-specific additions, plugins, and features to the Drupal CMS — used with NBCNews.com, TODAY.com and iVillage.com — working very closely with developers and engineers, outlining detailed specifications and requirements to ensure SEO success.

WorkWave (Formerly Marathon Data Systems)

Wall, NI

### Web Designer & SEO Specialist

October 2010 - March 2013

Web designer for WorkWave's marketing agency, with a focus on front-end design and web development for SEO efforts and overall conversion rate optimization.

### **Education**

Monmouth University

West Long Branch, NJ

**B.A.** History

December 2009